

Kay van den Aker

Designer and prototyper, exploring interactions that fuse digital and physical. Turning ambiguous ideas into experiences by gluing together various hard- and software.

Outside work, you can find him travelling, reading philosophy, or in the ocean doing various water sports. He's also been a surf instructor in Spain before.

Work Experience

2022 - Now Freelance

Interaction Designer and Prototyper (remote)

Currently for Google and Modem. Previously for Above, Hapticlabs, ProtoPie and Rolls-Royce.

2024 Archetype Al

Interaction Designer in Umeå, Sweden

Master thesis collaboration: Physical AI as an interaction design material.

2022 - 2023 Above

Design Technologist Intern in Malmö, Sweden

Working for various clients, from leading tech giants to small Scandinavian startups.

2022 Arduino

Content Creator in Malmö, Sweden uPython content and Docs redesign.

2021 BMW Group

Creative Technologist Intern in Munich, Germany

Experience prototyping at the concept car department, mostly on the Vision i Circular.

Designer / Co-Founder in Eindhoven, Netherlands

Student startup building an interactive map to simulate the impact of sustainable innovations on the energy grid.

Education

2021 – 2024 Umeå Institute of Design

MFA, Interaction Design
Class Representative

2016 – 2021 Eindhoven University of Technology

BSc (Hons), Industrial Design

Student council of the Honors Academy Chairman of Study Association Lucid Exchange at Umeå Institute of Design Surf committee of Avalanche Boarders

Technical Skills

Interaction Design
Experience Prototyping
Electronics and Programming

Arduino, ProtoPie, Unity, React, P5, HTML, CSS, JS, Python, Blender, SwiftUI, MadMapper, Laser-Cutting, Figma, 3D Printing, TouchDesigner

Contact

www.kayvandenaker.nl kayvandenaker@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/kayvandenaker